I'm Aaron Summers here with the Saints
latest offensive guard signing, David
Edwards. It's great to have you here.
What made the Saints your decision in
free agency?
>> Yeah, there's a lot of familiarity here
um between coaches and staff and um
people that I love and trust um that
made this process um really seamless
with with the information given about
the Saints and um what I know about that
and and just this place. Uh, it was the
right and perfect decision.
>> With what you know about the Saints, the
fan base, what do you like about the
culture that you're stepping into?
>> Yeah, I think there's a great tradition
of success here. There's a long history
of winning and and um great people.
That's the common theme I've heard um
being in New Orleans and being in this
building. And so um I just pair that
with, you know, the the familiarity with
people here. I just thought it was the
right decision for me and my family.
>> Taking it back to high school, I read
you were 210. You didn't eat breakfast
and you didn't lift. That doesn't track
for an offensive lineman. How much has
changed since then for you as a player?
>> A ton has changed. Yeah. Um the running
joke though when I was in high when I
was in high school was that I was going
to be an O lineman one day. Um for those
reasons. So I had a big frame. Um I was
pretty thin when I was in high school
and when I got to college it just kind
of naturally um the weight kept getting
uh pouring on. So um here we are. So
>> you're going to be joining an offensive
line that has Kelvin Banks Jr. there as
the left tackle. What have you seen from
his skill set that you're excited to
play alongside?
>> We had a crossover game last year with
the Jets late in the season. Um, and
being able to watch, you know, KB and
also all the other guys on the line, you
could see just how special this group
is, but specifically KB, you the first
thing that jumps off is his athleticism.
>> Um, what a special and unique talent he
is with his athleticism. And then the
tape that he was able to show last year,
he's going to be a really special
player. And so, the chance to get to
play next to him, I'm really excited
about. And, um, it's going to be it's
going to be awesome. really looking
forward to that.
>> As a vet stepping into this line, what
do you think your impact is going to be
able to be right off the bat?
>> I think I think initially I just want to
be able to establish myself and get gain
friendship and trust and and then from
there build within that. And so um I'm
hoping to be a leader alongside Eric
McCoy and Caesar Ruiz and these guys
that are have been here for a while. And
so um but the number one thing is that
whatever we do, we do it together. And
that's the most important thing with an
offensive line is is building trust
within each other, understanding um how
each guy is going to be able to block um
and then just having great communication
within that. And so that's what we're
going to build and continue to do. And I
know that there's a great foundation
here um already established.
>> What's the key to developing that
chemistry, especially with a young
quarterback and Tyler Chuck? I think
it's um the number one thing I I really
feel strongly about is the closer you
are to each guy,
>> the better the unit is. And so um going
to dinners with each other, you know,
having people over at the house and the
closer and the tighter the the group,
the better the group is. And so that
that's that's our goal. That's our
intent is to how close can we become as
friends and people and teammates so that
we can maximize our abilities on the
field.
>> You won a Super Bowl with the Rams. What
about that experience has helped your
continued drive?
>> I think that the the experiences that
you can draw within that is just um you
know what it takes and you know what it
looks like. And so, um, I've I've been
so blessed to have played with so many
great players, espec specifically on the
O line that have taught me those little
intricacies of, you know, being close as
as a unit, going to dinner, knowing each
other's families, um, having a great
understanding on technique and
fundamentals and how that plays into
each block. And there's so much that
goes into it, but ultimately it's how
close are you guys as friends and and
families cuz I think that drives your
success on the field.
>> A lot of great options here in New
Orleans for those dinners. I'm sure
you're looking forward to that aspect of
it. What do the fans need to know about
you as not just a player, but a person
as well?
>> That's a great question. Um I my wife is
here with our three-week old son, James.
Um you know, my family is everything. My
faith is everything. It's it's the
foundation of who I am. And um I hope
that, you know, the the people of New
Orleans, this building, get to see my
family and my kids um around and and are
invested in in this city um because
that's that's the foundation of who I
am. And so um alongside with that, just
just try to be the best version of
myself every day. and um as a football
player, as a person, a person of faith,
um you know, I'm just trying to be the
best version of of myself as I can be
every day.
>> What are you looking forward to most
about taking the field in the Super Dome
for your first game as a Saint?
>> Yeah. Um
there's so much to look forward to. Um
being able to play in in Kell's offense,
playing for Tyler, um playing with this
offensive line, playing in the
Superdome, being in this city. there's
just so much momentum and and excitement
from myself and my family that um
through this process that that I thought
about and and was hoping that you know
would come to fruition. So to kind of
put one thing down would be really tough
but um it's just all-encompassing a
really exciting opportunity.
>> We are looking forward to it too. Can't
wait to see you on the field coming up
soon training camp and then the season.
So, congratulations and we look forward
to having you here.
>> Thank you very much.